// Quiz data
final Map<int, List<Map<String, dynamic>>> chapterQuizzes = {
  1: [
    {
      'question':
          'A localized group of organisms that belong to the same species is called a:',
      'options': ['Biosphere', 'Community', 'Ecosystem', 'Population'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Population',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Increased quantity and quality of fish production:',
      'options': ['Fisheries', 'Farming', 'Animal husbandry', 'Forestry'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Fisheries',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Study of remote past organic life, with the help of fossils.',
      'options': ['Entomology', 'Paleontology', 'Taxonomy', 'Histology'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Paleontology',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Laws and techniques of physics are applied to explain the living processes of life.',
      'options': ['Biometry', 'Biostatistics', 'Biophysics', 'Bio-economics'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Biophysics',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Choose the incorrect statement:',
      'options': [
        'Six elements such as C, H, O, N, S, and P are called basic elements of life.',
        'Foundation of life based on chemicals.',
        'Members of different species form population.',
        'Part of the earth where life exists is called biosphere.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'Part of the earth where life exists is called biosphere.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Science of diagnosis and treatment of diseases.',
      'options': ['Agriculture', 'Medicine', 'Surgery', 'Both B and C'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Medicine',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Similar cells combine together to form:',
      'options': ['Organs', 'System', 'Tissue', 'Body'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Tissue',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Scientific name of frog is:',
      'options': ['Palaeon', 'Rana tigrina', 'Periplaneta', 'Pheretima'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Rana tigrina',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the correct sequence of biological organization',
      'options': [
        'Atom → Cell → Tissue → Molecule → Organ',
        'Atom → Tissue → Cell → Molecule → Organ',
        'Atom → Molecule → Cell → Tissue → Organ',
        'Atom → Cell → Molecule → Tissue → Organ',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Atom → Cell → Molecule → Tissue → Organ',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Volvox is a polyphyletic genus of',
      'options': ['Green algae', 'Red algae', 'Brown algae', 'None of these'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Green algae',
    },
  ],

  2: [
    {
      'question': 'Select the correct sequence of biological method.',
      'options': [
        'Law → Theory → Reasoning → Hypothesis',
        'Hypothesis → Theory → Law → Reasoning',
        'Hypothesis → Reasoning → Theory → Law',
        'Law → Hypothesis → Reasoning → Theory',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Hypothesis → Reasoning → Theory → Law',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the odd one.',
      'options': ['Theory', 'Law', 'Hypothesis', 'Ratio'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Ratio',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Field of research that examines mathematical representations of biological system called.',
      'options': ['Ratio', 'Mathematical biology', 'Proportion', 'Law'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Mathematical biology',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Biological method involves all of the following except.',
      'options': ['Data collection', 'Observation', 'Experiment', 'Proportion'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Proportion',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Scientific reasoning moves from specific to general.',
      'options': ['Inductive', 'Deductive', 'Observation', 'Both a and b'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Inductive',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Quantitative observation is the use of.',
      'options': ['Senses', 'Equipment', 'Guess', 'Ratio'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Equipment',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Equation stating that two ratios are equal.',
      'options': ['Ratio', 'Proportion', 'Guess', 'Senses'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Proportion',
    },
    {
      'question': 'The comparison of two values is called.',
      'options': ['Ratio', 'Proportion', 'Graph', 'Table'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Ratio',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What is a hypothesis?',
      'options': [
        'The same thing as an unproven theory.',
        'A tentative explanation that can be tested and is falsified.',
        'A verifiable observation.',
        'A fact based on quantitative data that is falsified.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'A tentative explanation that can be tested and is falsified.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'In data organization, which method is mostly useful?',
      'options': ['Table', 'Graph', 'Ratio', 'Both a and b'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Both a and b',
    },
  ],

  3: [
    {
      'question':
          'Which of the following is the correct way of writing a scientific name of an organism?',
      'options': ['Houbara bustard', 'E. coli', 'Allium cepa', 'Canis lupus'],
      'correctAnswer': 'E. coli',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the mismatched',
      'options': [
        'Plantae → Pteridophyta',
        'Fungi → Mucor',
        'Protista → Paramecium',
        'Animalia → Amoeba',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Animalia → Amoeba',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Identify the correct sequence of classifying an organism.',
      'options': [
        'Species → Genus → Kingdom → Phylum → Class → Order → Family',
        'Kingdom → Phylum → Class → Order → Family → Genus → Species',
        'Kingdom → Phylum → Class → Family → Order → Genus → Species',
        'Species → Genus → Class → Phylum → Order → Kingdom → Family',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'Kingdom → Phylum → Class → Order → Family → Genus → Species',
    },
    {
      'question': 'All are involved in classification except',
      'options': ['Analogous', 'Homologous', 'Cytology', 'Genetics'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Cytology',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'In the taxonomic hierarchy, choose the term which encompasses all others in the list (I) Genus, (II) Species, (III) Order, (IV) Class',
      'options': ['I and II', 'II', 'II and III', 'IV'],
      'correctAnswer': 'IV',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'In four kingdom classification, kingdom Metaphyta includes all of the following except.',
      'options': ['Algae', 'Angiosperm', 'Gymnosperm', 'Bryophyta'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Algae',
    },
    {
      'question': 'In the five-kingdom system, viruses are placed in',
      'options': ['Monera', 'Protista', 'Plantae', 'None of these'],
      'correctAnswer': 'None of these',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Biological name of a cat',
      'options': [
        'Felis catus',
        'Azadirachta indica',
        'Allium cepa',
        'Canis lupus',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Felis catus',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Members of which kingdom have cell walls and are all heterotrophic',
      'options': ['Monera', 'Protista', 'Plantae', 'Fungi'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Fungi',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Biodiversity is affected by (I) Pollution, (II) Deforestation, (III) Overhunting',
      'options': ['I only', 'II only', 'I and II', 'I, II, and III'],
      'correctAnswer': 'I, II, and III',
    },
  ],

  4: [
    {
      'question':
          'What is responsible for the high resolution of the electron microscope?',
      'options': [
        'High magnification',
        'Short wavelength of the electron beam',
        'Use of heavy metals strains',
        'Very thin section',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Short wavelength of the electron beam',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What is the function of the rough endoplasmic reticulum?',
      'options': [
        'Aerobic respiration',
        'Intracellular digestion',
        'Synthesis of steroids',
        'Synthesis of protein',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Synthesis of protein',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Which statement about the fluid mosaic model of membrane structure is correct?',
      'options': [
        'The less unsaturated the fatty acid, the more fluid nature.',
        'The more unsaturated the fatty acid, the more fluid nature.',
        'Higher the temperature, less fluid nature.',
        'The lower the temperature, more fluid nature',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'The more unsaturated the fatty acid, the more fluid nature.',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Which process allows movement in and out of the cell I. Osmosis, II. Diffusion, III. Active transport',
      'options': [
        'I only',
        'I and II only',
        'II and III only',
        'I, II, and III',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'I, II, and III',
    },
    {
      'question': 'All are postulates of cell theory except',
      'options': [
        'New cell is derived from pre-existing cells.',
        'Cell does not contain the hereditary material.',
        'All living organisms are made up of one or more cells.',
        'Cell is the fundamental unit of life',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Cell does not contain the hereditary material.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Secondary wall is made up of',
      'options': [
        'Pectin and cellulose',
        'Cellulose and protein',
        'Cellulose and lignin',
        'Lignin and pectin',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Cellulose and lignin',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the odd one',
      'options': [
        'Active transport',
        'Diffusion',
        'Facilitated diffusion',
        'Osmosis',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Facilitated diffusion',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Trace the correct pathway of protein produced from protein factories',
      'options': [
        'RER → Ribosome → Golgi body → Lysosome',
        'Ribosomes → RER → Golgi body → Lysosome',
        'Golgi body → RER → Ribosome → Lysosome',
        'RER → Ribosome → Lysosome → Golgi body',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Ribosomes → RER → Golgi body → Lysosome',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Cell organelle found in animal cell and helps intracellular digestion',
      'options': ['Lysosome', 'Ribosomes', 'Mitochondria', 'Golgi apparatus'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Lysosome',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the mismatched',
      'options': [
        'Plastids → Storage of chemicals',
        'Centriole → Help in cell division',
        'Ribosomes → Synthesis of steroids',
        'Mitochondria → Synthesis of ATP',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Ribosomes → Synthesis of steroids',
    },
  ],

  5: [
    {
      'question': 'Which processes involve mitosis?',
      'options': [
        'Growth, reduction division and asexual reproduction.',
        'Growth, repair and asexual reproduction.',
        'Growth, repair and semiconservative replication.',
        'Growth, reduction division and repair',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Growth, repair and asexual reproduction.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What occurs in metaphase of mitosis?',
      'options': [
        'Chromosome line up on the equator of the cell.',
        'Chromatids reach the poles of the spindle.',
        'Chromatids separate and move to opposite poles.',
        'Chromosomes start to coil up and become visible.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Chromosome line up on the equator of the cell.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the mismatched',
      'options': [
        'Anaphase → Chromatids move',
        'Prophase → Centriole move',
        'Telophase → Nuclear membrane disappear',
        'Metaphase → Chromosome line up.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Telophase → Nuclear membrane disappear',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Which process occurs during prophase of mitosis in an animal cell?',
      'options': [
        'Division of centromeres',
        'Formation of chromosomes',
        'Replication of DNA',
        'Separation of centrioles',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Separation of centrioles',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Sequence of physiological changes by which cell commit suicide.',
      'options': ['Apoptosis', 'Necrosis', 'Autophagy', 'Both "a" and "b"'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Apoptosis',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Choose the incorrect statement regarding meiosis.',
      'options': [
        'Maintain chromosome number from generation to generation.',
        'Reduces the diploid number of chromosomes to half',
        'Takes place in germ cell to produce gametes',
        'Production of new somatic cells from germ cells.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Production of new somatic cells from germ cells.',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'A type of cell division in which spore mother cell produces spores.',
      'options': ['Amitosis', 'Mitosis', 'Meiosis', 'Both "a" and "c"'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Meiosis',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Stage of mitosis in which chromatids reach the poles and their movement ceases.',
      'options': ['Prophase', 'Metaphase', 'Anaphase', 'Telophase'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Telophase',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Stage of meiosis in which centromeres shorten and the paired chromatids are pulled away from one another.',
      'options': ['Anaphase-II', 'Metaphase-II', 'Telophase-II', 'Prophase-II'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Anaphase-II',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Phenomenon in which a pair of homologous chromosomes fails to separate called.',
      'options': ['Non-disjunction', 'Terminalization', 'Synapsis', 'Linkage'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Non-disjunction',
    },
  ],

  6: [
    {
      'question': 'All are characters of enzymes except.',
      'options': [
        'Enzyme speed up a biochemical reaction.',
        'Enzymes are sensitive to minor changes in pH',
        'Enzyme activity enhanced by inhibitors',
        'Enzyme portion where substrate attach called active site',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Enzyme activity enhanced by inhibitors',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Enzymes are',
      'options': [
        'Steroid in nature',
        'Protein in nature',
        'Lipid in nature',
        'Carbohydrate in nature',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Protein in nature',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Metabolic reactions are: (I) Constructive reactions, (II) Destructive reactions, (III) Inhibiting reactions',
      'options': [
        'I only',
        'I and II only',
        'I, II, and III',
        'II and III only',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'I and II only',
    },
    {
      'question': 'The point where the enzyme is most active is known as',
      'options': ['Neutral pH', 'Acidic pH', 'Basic pH', 'Optimum pH'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Optimum pH',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Active site continuously changes its shapes until the substrate does not bind to it, is a statement of.',
      'options': [
        'Induce fit model',
        'Lock and key model',
        'Fluid mosaic model',
        'Both "a" and "b"',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Induce fit model',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Select the mismatched',
      'options': [
        'Proteases → Carbohydrate',
        'Lipases → Lipids',
        'Trypsin → Protein',
        'All are correctly matched',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Proteases → Carbohydrate',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Chemical reaction requires particular conditions to carry down at a proper rate, especially.',
      'options': [
        'Temperature and Nature',
        'Nature and Pressure',
        'Nature and Structure',
        'Temperature and Pressure',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Temperature and Pressure',
    },
    {
      'question': 'All are factors affecting enzyme activity except.',
      'options': [
        'pH',
        'Substrate concentration',
        'Organic solvent',
        'Temperature',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Temperature',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Rate of reaction will increase when temperature',
      'options': ['Increases', 'Decreases', 'Below 10°C', 'Both "a" and "c"'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Increases',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Choose the correct statement regarding the lock and key model.',
      'options': [
        'Enzyme and substrate possess specific complementary geometric shapes.',
        'Active site of the enzyme is flexible',
        'Active site continuously changes',
        'All above statements are correct.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'Enzyme and substrate possess specific complementary geometric shapes.',
    },
  ],

  7: [
    {
      'question':
          'In an oxidation process 14135 KJ energy is released, how many moles of glucose consume during this process.',
      'options': ['1', '3', '5', '10'],
      'correctAnswer': '3',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Stage of aerobic respiration takes place at the cristae of mitochondria called.',
      'options': [
        'Electron transport chain',
        'Glycolysis',
        'Kreb\'s cycle',
        'C3 cycle',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Electron transport chain',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'In a process of cellular respiration 180 ATP molecules are produced, how many moles of glucose consume during this process.',
      'options': ['2', '5', '8', '10'],
      'correctAnswer': '10',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Loss of electron and proton is called: (I) Oxidation reaction (II) Reduction reaction (III) Redox reaction',
      'options': ['I only', 'I and II', 'II and III', 'I, II and III'],
      'correctAnswer': 'I only',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Each mole of ATP stores energy',
      'options': [
        '7.3 kcal/mole',
        '7.3 kJ/mole',
        '17.3 kcal/mole',
        '17.3 kJ/mole',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': '7.3 kcal/mole',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Fundamental molecule produced during photosynthesis is',
      'options': ['Glucose', 'Amino acid', 'Fatty acid', 'Nucleotide'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Glucose',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Light-dependent reaction takes place in',
      'options': ['Stroma', 'Thylakoid', 'Cristae', 'Cisternae'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Thylakoid',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Reaction in which solar energy is transferred to glucose from ATP and NADPH, takes place in stroma called',
      'options': [
        'Light reaction',
        'Dark reaction',
        'Light-dependent reaction',
        'Light and Dark reactions',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Dark reaction',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Splitting of water in the presence of light is called',
      'options': ['Hydrolysis', 'Glycolysis', 'Photolysis', 'None of these'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Photolysis',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Splitting of glucose (glycolysis) releases a small amount of energy which is enough to generate',
      'options': ['2 ATP', '5 ATP', '18 ATP', '36 ATP'],
      'correctAnswer': '2 ATP',
    },
  ],

  8: [
    {
      'question': 'Select the mismatched',
      'options': [
        'Protein → Amino acid',
        'Carbohydrate → Glucose',
        'Fats → Starch',
        'Nucleic acid → Nucleotide',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Fats → Starch',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Deficiency of vitamin-K causes',
      'options': ['Rickets', 'Anemia', 'Scurvy', 'Beriberi'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Beriberi',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Period of rapid growth and development called',
      'options': ['Childhood', 'Adulthood', 'Adolescence', 'Both "a" and "b"'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Adolescence',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Deficiency of dietary protein causes an imbalance in the gastrointestinal system',
      'options': ['Marasmus', 'Edema', 'Diarrhea', 'Kwashiorkor'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Kwashiorkor',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'An animal that migrates great distances would obtain the greatest benefit from storing its energy as',
      'options': ['Fats', 'Carbohydrates', 'Protein', 'Minerals.'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Fats',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Which of the following vitamins is correctly associated with its use?',
      'options': [
        'Vitamin K → Production of white blood cells',
        'Vitamin C → Curing rickets',
        'Vitamin E → Protection of skin from cancer',
        'Vitamin A → Incorporated into the visual pigment of the eye',
      ],
      'correctAnswer':
          'Vitamin A → Incorporated into the visual pigment of the eye',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following statements describes pepsin?',
      'options': [
        'It is manufactured by the pancreas.',
        'It helps stabilize fat-water emulsions.',
        'It splits maltose into monosaccharides.',
        'It begins the hydrolysis of proteins in the stomach.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'It begins the hydrolysis of proteins in the stomach.',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of the following is true of bile salts?',
      'options': [
        'They are enzymes',
        'They are manufactured by the pancreas',
        'They emulsify fats in the duodenum',
        'They increase the efficiency of pepsin action.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'They emulsify fats in the duodenum',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'In the human digestive system trachea and esophagus both connect to the',
      'options': ['Large intestine', 'Stomach', 'Pharynx', 'Rectum'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Pharynx',
    },
    {
      'question': 'All are sources of calcium except',
      'options': ['Red meat', 'Green leafy vegetables', 'Broccoli', 'Nuts'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Nuts',
    },
  ],

  9: [
    {
      'question':
          'The movement of organic materials (food) takes place through',
      'options': ['Xylem', 'Vessels', 'Tracheid', 'Phloem'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Phloem',
    },
    {
      'question': 'What regulates the flow of water through the xylem?',
      'options': [
        'Passive transport by the endodermis',
        'The number of companion cells in the phloem',
        'The evaporation of water from the leaves',
        'Active transport by sieve-tube membrane',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'The evaporation of water from the leaves',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Phloem transport of sucrose can be described as going from "source to sink" which of the following would not normally function as a sink?',
      'options': [
        'Mature leaf',
        'Storage organ',
        'Growing root',
        'Both \'b\' and \'c\'',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Mature leaf',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Human plasma proteins include which of the following? (I) Fibrinogen (II) Haemoglobin (III) Albumin',
      'options': ['I only', 'II only', 'I and II', 'I and III'],
      'correctAnswer': 'I and III',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Which of these are involved in the clotting of blood?',
      'options': ['Platelets', 'Haemoglobin', 'Albumin', 'Globulin'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Platelets',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'In the human heart blood returning from lungs first drains into the',
      'options': [
        'Left atrium',
        'Left ventricle',
        'Right atrium',
        'Right ventricle',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Left atrium',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Root hairs are most important to a plant because they',
      'options': [
        'Store starch',
        'Contain xylem tissues',
        'Provide a habitat for nitrogen-fixing bacteria',
        'Increase the surface area for absorption.',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Increase the surface area for absorption.',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'A type of circulatory system blood flow through the spaces among tissues called.(I) Open type circulatory system, (II) Close type circulatory system, (III) Pulmonary circulatory system',
      'options': ['I only', 'II only', 'I and II', 'II and III'],
      'correctAnswer': 'I only',
    },
    {
      'question': 'Part of the root between epidermis and endodermis called',
      'options': ['Xylem', 'Root hair', 'Phloem', 'Cortex'],
      'correctAnswer': 'Cortex',
    },
    {
      'question':
          'Movement of water molecules from the area of higher water potential to the area of lower water potential called',
      'options': [
        'Diffusion',
        'Osmosis',
        'Active transport',
        'Water potential',
      ],
      'correctAnswer': 'Osmosis',
    },
  ],
};
